No, I think taste matters a ton. In a
world where it's easier to build things,
it's more important to make sure that
your time is spent figuring out what you
should be building in the first place.
The people who I think are going to make
the most of it are the ones who are
cleareyed about what AI is good at and
what it's not good at and also have an
instinct or a nose for what it will be
good at and not good at. What's
something that the Instagram algorithm
knows about human behavior that people
may not realize?
>> I think people assume that there's a
much more detailed semantic
understanding of everybody's interests
and preferences in the algorithm than
there is.
>> Is the rise of AI content a headwind or
a tailwind for Instagram versus other
platforms?
>> I think it's going to be a tailwind, but
I think it's going to be a challenge
[music] in a world where there's an
abundance of synthetic content. I
actually think people are going to seek
out creativity and authenticity and
people. I don't think we should filter
out AI content. I think we should
[music] let you know if content is AI
content or not. That's hard. By the way,
>> where do you think human brains will
continue to be most valuable as AI
continues to eat more and more of that
product development life cycle?
>> That's a great question. So
today my guest is Adam Masseri, head of
Instagram. Over three billion people use
Instagram monthly. That's one in every
three people alive. It boggles the mind.
Prior to Instagram, Adam designed and
led the early Facebook news feed. He
also ran the team that built the
Facebook ranking algorithm. And 8 years
ago, he took over Instagram from its
founders, Kevin Cyester [music] and Mike
Kger. He's a designer turned product
manager turned leader of Instagram. Adam
is also famous for being the face of all
of the controversy and changes that come
with evolving Instagram as a product,
which we talk about. Before we get into
it, don't forget to check out
lennisproduct.com [music]
for a free year of the most interesting
and well-crafted AI products in the
world, available exclusively to Lenny's
newsletter subscribers. With that, I
bring you Adam Masseri.
Adam, thank you so much for being here.
Welcome to the podcast.
>> Thank you for having me. Excited to be
here.
>> You've been doing product for a long
time. You get to see how a lot of teams
operate across Meta within Instagram.
What does just kind of like the
canonical product team look like in
2026? What's kind of most different
today in how teams operate slash should
operate versus say a couple years ago?
>> It's changed a lot this year. So for the
longest time at a big company like ours,
the canonical team was something like
two or three Android engineers, two or
three iOS engineers, two or three server
engineers,
maybe a generalist, a PM, a designer, a
data scientist, a researcher if you were
lucky,
and maybe that's about it. So you know
on the order of a baker's dozen and that
is a function of
you know you want to have for anybody
who's writing code someone who can
review their code and that's who's
familiar with that codebase and having
these different functions that are more
specialized you know I think it's very
different at a startup but this year
it's changing we've adopted what we call
pods which are just mini teams where
it's call it four to six engineers who
are a bit more generalists.
Uh one we call product staff which is
sort of an evolution of the PM. So a PM
who can do some of what a designer does
and some of what a data scientist does
and some of what a research does
leveraging um the latest tools that we
have for them. And then whatever
specialist they need if they if they're
doing something that requires a pricing
strategy you need a senior data
scientist. If you're doing something
that is really novel from an experience
standpoint, you need a very senior
product designer. So we try to build the
team based on the needs of the work a
bit, but then end up with a much smaller
core which is more on the order of six
or seven usually. And that is a very big
shift that's just happening to us this
year. But they
just by virtue of having less people to
coordinate they can often move faster
and make um better decisions a little
bit less design by committee. So we talk
a lot about you know AI adjusting and
improving productivity and that's part
of it but I think another part of it is
just
the small teams I think often are just
more effective. This episode is brought
to you by our season's presenting
sponsor, WorkOS. What do OpenAI,
Anthropic, Cursor, Versell, Replet,
Sierra, Clay, and hundreds of other
winning companies all have in common?
They are all powered by work OS. If
you're building a product for the
enterprise, you've felt the pain of
integrating single signon, skim,
arbback, audit logs, and other features
required by large companies. work OS
turns those deal blockers into drop-in
APIs with a modern developer platform
built specifically for B2B SAS. [music]
Literally every startup that I'm an
investor in that starts to expand up
market ends up working with Work OS. And
that's because they are the best.
Whether you are seedstage startup trying
to land your first enterprise customer
or a unicorn [music] expanding globally,
work OS is the fastest path to becoming
enterprise ready and unblocking growth.
It's essentially Stripe for enterprise
features. Visit works.com to get started
or just hit up their Slack where they
have actual engineers waiting to answer
your questions. Workos allows you to
build faster with delightful APIs,
[music]
comprehensive docs, and a smooth
developer experience. Go to work os.com
to make your app enterprise ready today.
I I love this. So on this team of six to
seven, what's what's the makeup again?
And which role are you finding you have
less of? If you're going from the kind
of the if you're going 50% size,
>> you just have less specialists, right?
So you might not [clears throat] have
any. You might be four engineers and a
product staff and there's no data
scientist, there's no designer, there's
no researcher, there's no content
designer. The product staff is the
generalist that sort of supports all of
those things. I mean, what's clearly
happening is all the functions are
starting to bleed into each other and
the and the whole industry is wrestling
with what that means.
You know, a lot of what a data scientist
does at a big company, for instance, is
relatively
mechanical. And so, you know, there's
stuff that they do that is really more
like, you know, art and science. And the
stuff that's really more like just
pulling data, data management, you know,
so some of the tools that we're building
internally to understand, for instance,
a traditional data science question
would be a waterfall. So if you wanted
to look at people creating reels, you
would look at all the steps and then how
people fall off on each step and try to
figure out where there might be
opportunities to improve things. That
kind of basic waterfall analysis is like
much easier now to use some of our
internal tools to just pull
automatically as opposed to having to
have a data scientist do a bunch of
bespoke work for that. So a product
staff might be able to do that now and
they couldn't do that a year ago. So you
just end up with this generalist these
people who have more generalist shapes
and then and then when you need it when
you really need it you have a more
senior ideally or just more creative
specialist um so you know a phenomenal
uh product designer or just a just a
genius uh data scientist or researcher.
>> This is so interesting. It's exactly
what I just heard. I had uh Fiona Fong
the head of engineering for cloud code
and co-work on the podcast. She's force
attorney's manager and she described the
people she hires now are one builders
with great taste that can take an idea
from end to end and people with deep
expertise in a very specific domain.
>> The tasting matters a lot. I really
agree with that. Boris used to work at
Instagram. Um I love
>> Yeah. He was a senior IC at Instagram
for a while. I love seeing him. He's all
over threads now. It's like he's sort of
like the face of Clark K. He's he's a
celebrity now. He really is. He's his
own little Yeah, for sure. In a world
that is like on fire right now. Um, no,
I think taste matters a ton. Uh, so in a
world where it's easier to build things,
it's more important to make sure that
your time is spent figuring out what you
should be building in the first place.
Um, actually, so a lot of designers
right now are very anxious about their
roles. you know, you've got these other
generalists doing design, you've got
engineers doing design, product staff
doing design, but I'm actually pretty
long on design or designers because they
tend to have taste and I think that is
something that is
much more difficult to imagine being
automated away. And so there's other
challenges with design sometimes, but I
I'm pretty long right now on designers.
I've always felt that too as it is so
easy to build and all the work that AI
produces is so like you can tell this
was cloud design. I know what you did
here.
>> This is codeex.
>> Well, they all have their vibe, right?
Like you vibe code your apps. We call it
vibe coding. You're all like, "Oh,
that's a codeex app." Or, "Oh, that's a
cloud app."
>> Right. And that's replet. That's
lovable. Like you can
>> Yeah.
>> You can predict these things. You like
I've always thought that too that design
should be thriving already now. For some
reason, it hasn't yet. If you look at
jobs for designers, they're kind of
flatlining. I feel like the missing
piece is like the PM piece of deeply
understanding the business and what will
grow it and what success, you know, like
all that stuff, the business side of it
versus the taste side of it.
>> Yeah. I think you're going to see like,
you know, um we have a senior designer
uh at Instagram uh called Nate who just
transferred into product stuff. So, I
think I think some of what you'll see
is, you know, it will be harder to talk
about design roles and who's a good
designer because they're not going to
just stay in traditional design roles.
You know, if you're an amazing designer,
you might you probably have strong
opinions outside of just the interaction
in visual design. You probably have
strong opinions on product strategy,
even on the business, on the go to
market. And so I actually think some of
our strongest product staff are going to
be converts from design and from data
science who are just looking to expand
their reach. And they were influential
across functional boundaries before, but
this world where those functional
boundaries are just wildly blurred just
allow them just to jump in. And so sure
they'll be technically a generalist on
paper, but they're they're clearly have
a a uniquely, you know, strong ability
in one one type of craft. Um, but
they've got the ability and strong
opinions to make informed decisions
across other parts or other crafts. And
so, you know, I don't know that all the
strongest designers I have will all be
in design. They they probably will be
the majority, but I can imagine a bunch
of really strong ones, you know, moving
roles, but I mean, I should also check
my own bias here, though, because I
started as a designer at Facebook way
back when, and I'm I switched roles. Um,
>> no, designers are great. I'm a big fan.
So, this is really interesting. There's
always been this like GM model where
different types of functions can become
GMs. It's like this product staff role
feels like a similar situation where
different functions can become product
staff.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And that was true of PM
before, but it's just so much more true
now. Um and it'll I mean in some ways
it's probably the age of the generalist,
but I I still think there's going to be
a real important role for these really
amazing specialists who are just they're
all about going I wish I was like that.
I always had this like I romanticized
like the phenomenal machine learning
engineer or AI researcher or shoe maker.
Like I think that's the coolest thing in
the world, but it's never been my shape.
I've always been um I've never been
great at anything. I've always just had
range. That's always been my strength.
Same. [laughter]
Okay. So this idea of product staff, so
the idea is on these new pods. So this
is like a new thing you guys are doing.
So there's these pod teams, product
staff, engineers, and maybe one
specialist that's going deep on say
pricing algorithm or something like
that. So what this tells me is there's
these like adjacent roles that are maybe
uh more in trouble over the years. Uh
data science for example, user research
for example, you talked about designers
being anxious. Is there is there
anything there of just like oh these
maybe folks in these groups should think
about shifting to other roles?
>> I I mean there's anxiety everywhere. I
mean, I I I've talked to a lot of people
at a lot of other companies, and it just
seems like this is a lot of concern
right now about competition, about job
displacement, about unintended or
unforeseen consequences of all this
technology and all this moving so
quickly. So, that's definitely
happening. I I think that I think that
you will see the functional lines
continue to blur, but I still think
there will be room for functions.
They'll just be shaped differently.
They'll be more they won't all be senior
IC's necessarily, but they'll all be
either senior or on their way to being
senior. Like you can't just have a bunch
of super senior data scientists and like
no new ones because then who's going to
be the new super data scientists in the
future. So you need to basically hire
and mentor and grow talent. You know,
maybe the team is smaller overall and
then that those who aren't on their way
to being super senior move into more of
a generalist role. I think that's like a
reasonable soft landing, but I do think
you're going to want to make sure you're
investing not only in today's senior
talent for each specific function, but
in tomorrow's. Um, otherwise, I think
you're going to regret it in a couple
years. My take. That said, who knows
what the world looks like in a couple
years. Um, so my big thing and is
generally like don't over don't be
overly confident in whatever your
predictions are because there's just too
much flux right now. the Benedict Evans
was on was on the podcast recently said
the same thing. We don't know anything
about what's going on.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I like I like I like him a
lot. Um I'll make sure I listen to the
podcast.
>> Yeah. So you talked about taste. This
makes me think about So you're
interviewing a lot of people, hiring a
lot of people. What are some traits that
you're that are like trending up in
things that you look for more and more
now in this world? And what are some
traits that are trending down and maybe
less important to you?
>> I mean there are some things that are
the same, right? So, for the longest
time, almost no matter what the
function, I always look for three
things. Do you have sort of grit? Like,
you know, you're kind of like you're
really gonna you've got some drive, some
fire in your belly. Are you a quick
learner? And
are you, you know, are you reasonably,
ideally, very self-aware so that you can
actually take feedback and know what
you're good at, know what you're good
at? Because if you're those three
things, if you got fire in your belly,
you learn quickly, and you're
self-aware, you can kind of get good at
anything eventually. Um, and but if any
of those things are missing, there's
usually an issue. So that's sort of like
the baseline
right now for hiring, but just for I
think people who are going to be
more successful over these next five or
10 years as things change so
significantly.
I think two things that I I'm continuing
to encourage myself to do are to stay
curious and to put yourself out there. I
just think you got to try things, right?
This is like, you know, to that point
before where that no one really knows
what's going on. You just have to be
willing to try things. It's almost I
don't know. Do you speak another
language?
>> Uh, Russian. Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, when you learn another
language, I think one of the most
important things, one of the best
predictors, this is my guess. I don't
have any research on this about, you
know, are you going to get good at
speaking is are you willing to sound
like an idiot? Are you willing just to
say it and be corrected and not be
offended and then just get better and
better? You just have to put yourself
out there. And with all of these new
tools and models and technologies, I
think you just have to be willing to try
stuff. Um, so if you're curious and you
try stuff, I think that'll, you know,
you'll learn, you'll adapt. But if
you're not curious or you're not willing
to make mistakes or try things, I think
you're in a ton of trouble. Uh, or at
least I think it's going to be a really
difficult time. So those I think are
premiums, not just for hiring at a
company like Meta or a team like
Instagram, but I just think across the
industry and multiple industries over
the next 10 or 20 years. Is there
something that maybe we're looking for
less of for some of these functions? Um,
I think that there's some that are still
going to be very large teams and so you
need people who are really good at
managing large organizations. Large
organizational leadership is its own
craft and skill. It's actually different
than management. Um, but I do think
there'll be less of those roles. I think
we'll have more smaller teams and
there'll be less people who manage
thousands of people. Um, and so that's
not that that job will go away, but that
will be less of what I'm looking for in
hires because I'm going to have less
roles like that.
>> Something I'm hearing from a few folks
is AI is almost kind of resetting
people's impact and success in terms of
some people that were maybe low
performers pre-AII can now do like
things they were bad at or AI now allows
them to do and now they're thriving,
building all these things, helping other
people. Do you see that at all? Just
like AI is just like lifting other
people up, maybe lowering some people
down.
>> Yeah. I mean the job is just different.
I mean take take us take um take
engineering. Engineering used to be
maybe not majority but a large
percentage 40 50 60%
writing code. You know it's not now
especially if you talk to anybody at
these labs they're spending most of
their time planning and reviewing code.
That is a very different job. You might
hate that and you might have loved just
writing code or you might have you might
love that and you might not have been
that fast at writing code. So you know
who who succeeds is a function of whose
strengths are aligned with the tools
needs and the business's needs. And so
this is definitely happening. Another
thing is you've had people who had good
ideas about how to contribute to other
functions but didn't have the mechanical
or technical skills to do so and AI
reduces the boundary to do that and then
all of a sudden they can't like you know
I it's for me it's kind of funny because
when I got hired at Facebook we all the
designers had to be able to program that
was like our I had I went through a
technical loop we gave up on that
because it was too hard to hire people
um but I now get to program again for
the first time in maybe 10 years and you
know I am not a good engineer. I'm a
mediocre engineer on a good day but now
I can write code responsibly which is
just an amazing thing. You're seeing
this across all sorts of levels and
seniority and functions. you know,
designers who are programming, uh,
engineers who are pulling data and doing
strong analyses, data scientists who are
putting together proposals for designs.
You know, the tools aren't all great. By
the way, I think too often we have this
really polarized binary outlook on the
state of AI, like are you AI pill or are
you anti- AI? It's like people aren't
binary. I said that to the team
yesterday and the state of the tools
isn't binary either. You know, they're
amazing at some things and remarkably
bad at others. And the people who I
think are going to make the most of it
are the ones who are cleareyed about
what AI is good at and what it's not
good at and also have an instinct or a
nose for what it will be good at and not
good at, you know, not, you know, next
month or in a couple months from now.
you mentioned um that AI writes all our
code now. Someone tweeted this that's
this idea that stuck with me for like
months now of just like remember we used
to be able to just write code for free.
[laughter]
>> I think you'll still be able to write
code for free. It'll just be with a
smaller model. But yes,
>> I guess that's true. Like there's models
that are close to free but it's like
yeah that's crazy. Now it's just like
>> but just think about think about the
cost. Think about what you pay for a a
model now and how and what the level of
intelligence you're getting from that
model is and then at that same price
point a year ago what were you getting
at some point they will just the the
incremental value is will be won't
matter like you know you know we're
getting there I think with small
projects and programming like I I think
the models will matter even beyond you
know this week you've got fable and
obviously mythos from Enthropic, but I
spent a lot of time with that this week.
I'm it's for the first time I'm like,
"Oh, I'm just talking to a much more
technical, much smarter engineer than I
am." You know, the next version, you
know, you know, a year out of that
model. Do I need to pay for Frontier
tokens, you know, for whatever, you
know, anthropic model 6.0 is or is Fable
just fine for all of my side projects?
Probably just fine. probably pretty
pretty cheap by then, too.
>> Yeah. When Kevin Whale was on the
podcast when he was CPO at uh OpenAI,
he's he famously said, "This is the
worst the model will ever be."
>> Yeah.
>> Still hard to comprehend that. Wow.
That's it's only going to get better.
>> So, on this point of uh token spend,
ROI, and things like that,
>> uh Meta was famous for this like
leaderboard of token spend. Um
>> it's a terrible idea. No leaderboards
for token spend.
>> Okay. talk about that and just how do
you think about just like budgets for
engineers and product teams at this
point? You just like spend as much as
you want? Is it like there's a cap we
have? Is there any sort of thing you've
kind of figured out that works well?
>> Right now we've managed to get the costs
rained in a little bit by like shutting
down the silly things that we were
doing. And so, you know, it's not that
hard to build a token incinerator and
that doesn't create a lot of value. And
as soon as you actually look at the
dollars in and value out, you might just
be like, "Oh, that's just a bad idea."
And so right now we don't have um token
limits for for for our engineers
actually I think for anybody really. Uh
I think that'll eventually have to
happen um particularly if costs go up
before they go down. I think they'll
eventually go down because for the
reasons that we just talked about but I
think of it like as any other resource
right like I have to decide how to
deploy capacity to my different teams
because I have a limited number of GPUs
and CPUs and storage and RAM etc. I have
to decide how to deploy opex for
labeling budgets across my teams. I have
to decide how to deploy payroll for
headcount across my teams. I think that
you can imagine at least in an year or
two coming that the the burn rate of a
strong engineer might be the same as
their salary or their cost of
employment. And if in that world like
you're going to probably need to put in
some caps. the cap should probably be
com like a proportional to your sort of
you know the company's sort of trust in
your ability to use them in an ROI
positive way but I can imagine caps
being healthy right now we're not there
uh I think costs will go up because
we'll just be using more tokens not
because prices will necessarily go up
but then I think prices will come down
because all of these frontier models are
going to be in a bit of a pricing more.
Um, so we'll see. I think it'll be a bit
of a roller coaster.
>> So, coming back to this idea that as you
said, we've evolved from we used to
write all our code to now we're
approaching all code will be written by
AI. And it feels like now the transition
is it's not just written by AI, but it's
like oneshotted by AI. Like coding now
is steering AI and it's like how often
you have to correct it is is coding now.
And then there's uh so it's like the
software development life cycle slowly
being eaten by AI. Uh it'll start
helping us come up with ideas I imagine
more and more. The question I like to
ask people is where do you think human
brains will continue to be most valuable
as AI continues to eat more and more of
that product development life cycle.
taste like we talked about um judgment
particularly around strategy right like
you're you're not you might get feedback
from an AI on a strategy but you're not
asking an AI to come up with a strategy
anytime soon or if you are then it's
within the context of bounds you set so
here's my goal here's my vision here are
my constraints here's my job here's my
budget I think that you know it looks
more like management right like you are
trying to define what success looks like
decide how prescriptive you want to be
about the path to success and then
giving feedback along the way and that
is its own craft you know and you it'll
be interesting to see how Matt you know
you know some of the same dynamics come
up like I believe that if you are too
prescriptive as a leader with a team you
end up stifling good ideas but if you're
too open-ended sometimes teams just
waste time um going in the wrong
direction. And so that level of autonomy
you give a team like maybe that applies
to, you know, agents in the future. Um,
particularly when we're talking not just
about building something, but deciding
what you build in the first place. But I
think of I think of vision as an
articulation of the world or the or the
state of the product you want to get to.
Then I think of strategy is an
opinionated path to achieve that vision.
If a strat strategy can't be like be the
best or be amazing. It has to be
controversial that you have to be a
reasonable person should be able to
disagree with it because otherwise
you're probably just trying to compete
on raw execution and I think there both
vision and strategy I think are going to
be where our brains are spending a lot
of our more and more of our cycles and I
think less on on execution. Something I
have always thought is AI should be
incredibly good at strategy. Because you
would think here's the market, here's
all the information on the market, our
competitors, our metrics, our numbers,
our growth, all these things. Help me
figure out how to win. You think AI
knowing all that would be really good at
this. I think it could be. I I have
found it's not unless you steer it
pretty aggressively. And I don't mean
towards an answer. I mean based on the
constraints. It turns out when you're
trying to come up with a strategy,
there's a lot of things to consider,
right? You need to consider the state of
the technology, the personnel on the
team and what's motivating them and what
you can get. You know, sometimes coming
up with a idea that is on the bubble,
you know, it's going to actually attract
some of the best talent and so that kind
of like that kind of the push then goes
to the idea. uh obviously the
competitive landscape, the regulatory
landscape for companies as large as ours
and the compliance landscape, the
identity and reason to exist for the
brand. Um, you know, you have to
consider all of these things. I think if
you ask an AI just for a strategy
lazily, you're not going to get
something great. You're going to get
something pretty predictable that
probably the competition would expect
you to do. I think if you want a really
more effective one, you need to think
long and hard about what are all the
different inputs that need to be
considered. Make sure you
steer the AI in a way that it's
considering those as well. And it needs
to be a conversation and the back and
forth. But I think if you're willing to
put in the work and the time, it can
definitely be helpful and definitely be
clarifying. Um, particularly if you tell
it to be critical. Different models have
very different vibes though on Yeah.
>> How willing they are to be pushed back.
So [laughter] I I recommend picking one
that likes pushing back.
>> Yeah. Mythos has gotten really good at
being like, I can't do this. Let's let's
move on. Like uh there's all these
>> fun has always been a little bit of a
jerk in a way that I actually
appreciate.
>> I truly
>> I appreciate it. I really do because I
don't want one that's just like, "Oh,
you're so right. I'm so sorry I said
that." It's like, "No, hold on. I want I
want, you know, I want the real real
sort of intelligence. I don't want the
pleaser.
This point you made about people being
excited about the strategy is such an
interesting one. There's this idea that
I read I think Cy Corey Doctr wrote
this. There's this kind of concept of a
centaur centaur and a reverse centaur.
So centaur is a human body horse. This
is going somewhere I promise. Uh human
body uh horse sorry human upper part
lower part
>> horse body. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Horse body where the human is in charge.
And that's kind of we prefer that we
want to be in charge. reverse end chart,
which is what we want to avoid with AI,
is where the AI is controlling us and
we're just doing its bidding.
>> It's a horse head on a human body.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> It's terrifying.
>> Like in a sense like Uber drivers and
Door Dash people kind of this is their
life, which is not great
>> and [clears throat] this is the danger
thing for a lot of people is like like
if it's giving us the strategy and
telling us here's what we're built, like
no one's gonna want to do that. So
that's a really interesting counterpoint
to we don't want AI to be telling us the
strategy almost.
>> Yeah. No, I I I think there's
a lot of things to be careful about
right now. And I would certainly
not just assume that because you might
be able to outsource some workflow to AI
that you should. Um there are certain
ones where I think it's really just a
win-win. There are certain ones where I
think is the risk outweighs the
benefits. This episode is brought to you
by Mercury. Radically different banking
loved by over 300,000 entrepreneurs and
now with command. I've been a customer
of Mercury's for over 6 years. I have
never once thought about leaving.
Mercury is basically what happens when
banking is built by product people, not
by bankers. [music] They make it so
easy, dare I say fun, to send invoices,
move money around, set up virtual cards
for folks on my team. Does your bank
have an API, a terminal [music] native
CLI, or an AI ready MCP server? I don't
think so. And just recently, they
launched Command, a conversational
interface built directly into Mercury,
which acts as your financial operator.
I've been using [music] Command to
transfer money around to figure out what
categories I've been spending the most
money [music] in, analyze my cash flows,
and just today, I used it to find out
how much I've made from a specific
sponsor over the past year. I just
asked, "How much have I made from X over
the past year?" 10 seconds later, I have
an answer. It [music] is so freaking
cool. Visit mercury.com to learn more
and apply online in minutes. Mercury is
a fintech company, not an FDIC insured
bank. Banking services provided through
Choice Financial Group and column NA
members FDIC.
Okay, going back to product leadership,
things you've learned along your
journey. Uh, we were chatting ahead of
this about just things you've learned
and one thing that you said about some
of the product the best product leaders
you've worked with is that they're less
visionary and more curators. I'd love to
hear more along these lines. Yeah, I
mean you do sometimes find amazing
product leaders who are who are just
like idea machines, just prolific idea
machines. But I do think a lot of the
best are have have taste are
have something about them that really
makes wants makes really strong talent
want to work with them but end up sort
of being curators. curators of people,
curators of ideas, curators of
technologies, curators of strategies,
because I don't really care if I'm
hiring a strong lead for an area if the
strategy comes from them or comes from
somebody else. I just care that there is
a amazing strategy and everyone has
bought into it and that the and then
we're executing against that strategy
well. And so I think that some of the
best product leaders, yes, have ideas.
It's hard to be a great curator if you
don't have some of your own ideas, but
are
that embrace the reality that they can't
come up with everything themselves. And
so they need to create an environment in
which great ideas bubble up and are
uh chosen or decided upon. And so, you
know, I think it's not just about
curating ideas, but it's sometimes about
curating teams and people.
>> I love that. I so agree. I feel like
everyone's always joining a team and
they just want to do vision strategy
just like not actually hands-on work and
no AI is coming in here. Let me do the
strategy.
>> Exactly.
>> And I love this point that there's so
much power and value and people
underestimate just the the need for just
like a really good curator of of the
team's ideas.
>> Yeah. Sometimes it's also sometimes it's
not just who's good or what idea is
good. It's also what is going to work
given the broader context. So for
instance on team building a huge thing
that I'm always considering is not just
like is this person a really strong
candidate for this role. it is how does
this person fit into their leadership
team you know so if I you know for some
an area like trust and safety you know I
have an engineering lead I have a
product staff lead I have a data science
lead I have a design lead I have a
research lead you know I need to make
sure that those five complement each
other I need to make and that's you know
about what skills each one has what
weaknesses each one might have I also
need to make sure that they um this is
more art than science have a good vibe,
right? You know, you need, you know,
trust and rapport. A leadership team
with strong trust and rapport can work
through most anything. A leadership team
without trust or rapport, like anything
can become an issue. And so that that
chemistry bit is is is like I said much
more art than science, but that also
matters. And so I think some of the best
leaders and product leaders specifically
also
either do that instinctively or
consciously, but you know they have a
they have a nose for for building teams
that are going to have good energy and
um good collaboration,
>> warm and fuzzy stuff.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, the flip is also true,
right? Like I've I've had many times in
my career I've had two people who I
think are amazing and I even adore them
and love them and they just can't get
along. [laughter]
You're like this isn't a competency
issue. This is just a personality issue
and you just have to just sometimes call
it and split them.
>> I want to transition talk to talk about
Instagram the product the platform
things you guys have learned there. Let
me start with this question. What's
something that the Instagram algorithm
knows about human behavior that people
may not realize?
>> One of the most common misconceptions is
actually in the opposite direction. I
think people assume that there's a much
more detailed semantic understanding of
everybody's interests and preferences in
the algorithm than there is. Most of
what's really driven the progress in the
world of recommenders over the last 5 10
years have been,
you know, these large embedding models
and these other techniques that
basically produce artifacts that cannot
be read by people. They're not legible.
They're like giant vectors. It's like,
sure, I can show you the vector, but
it's just going to be a bunch of numbers
in like a seven dimensional space. It's
like, and so when when we talk about
does the algorithm know something,
usually we think in these more semantic
terms. It knows I like surfing and it's
like it doesn't. It just has this big
ass number that happens to correlate
with surfing. Um,
that said, I think that is starting to
change, right? I think that what
one of the things that LLMs are enabling
is they can describe in you know words
you know English for or whatever
language you prefer what some of those
previously illeible artifacts um are at
least approximate to if not mean
directly right so this is like the thing
I've been really I posted about this
this week this thing called your
algorithm basically the idea is we take
a look at all of the stuff that you've
interacted with. And then you know we
all of that is in an embedding space.
You can think of embedding space as a
map. You can map a bunch of videos into
the same map. And so videos that are
close or similar. And now we can just
have an LLM just be like describe that
part of the map. And it can be like oh
that is like deep pourover coffee
snobbery.
Um and that's kind of amazing.
>> That is so cool
>> that like you can ask the LM to look at
these numbers and extrapolate. here's
like the topic that you're interested
in.
>> Yeah. Or look at the videos.
>> And so the way you um both So you can
also embed concepts into that same
space. And so I mean embeddings are
really the underlying technology
underneath LLMs, right? That's how all
the whole thing works. And so you know,
so what what we what we what we do now
is we let you, you know, quote unquote
see your algorithm. You can see what
topics we think you're interested in. Um
and you can adjust it. You can add and
remove things, but the idea here giving
people some agency back in a world
where, you know, these social media apps
are getting taken over by
recommendations,
but we can't do a lot of other things
yet, which we will be able to do. You
know, you could there's things that
aren't topical that you might ask for. I
want more fun content. I want to see my
friends more. I don't want to see my
high school's kids friends kids photos.
You know, I don't know. We can come up
with I don't want to see seven photos in
a row, but I'm happy to see six photos
in a whatever your heart can, you know,
whatever your mind can come up with. So,
we have a lot of work to do. And so, I'm
excited about that. But, um, I think a
misconception historically is until
recently, we don't really know as much
about you as you think. We were just
like, oh, like you liked these photos,
this these people also like those same
photos and they like these other photos,
so you might like those other photos.
Like that's kind of how I'm
oversimplifying, but that's like
>> yeah,
>> kind of how it worked. Now only now are
we actually getting as sophisticated as
I think people have assumed we've been
for many years.
>> That is really interesting. One that
comes to mind is kind of this transition
everyone eventually goes through to this
like algorithmic
broad global feed. Uh everyone it always
feels like people think I just want to
see chronologically everyone I know and
follow and that's going to be my
favorite feed and it continues to be
proven wrong. No, you actually engage a
lot more a lot more when it's this
algorithmic feed of things we think you
will love. Yeah, it's tough because I
mean I get I mean I posted this week
this thing about agency and I just got
destroyed in the comments which is just
part of the job. I get it right. Um do
you there's but there are a couple
issues with the algorith with the
chronological feed. So one is and some
of this is the tension between an
individual's interests and what works
when you scale it up, right? So if you
do a pure chronological feed, the
incentive for everybody is to just post
as much as possible uh because it will
always be at the top of everyone who
follows you's feed as soon as you post.
So what ends up happening is that the
feed gets overwhelmed with professional
content with usually large company
content and publishers because they get,
you know, the New York Times can pump
out 50 things a day. your your best
friend won't
you might get one thing a week from them
and so your fee just gets taken over. Um
so part of it is the incentives that
emerge because when you when you design
these systems it's almost like designing
a city. You need to think about okay
here's the here are the here's how the
mechanics work. What are the incentives
that arise? How are people going to act
within those incentives? And then what
happens? And the other thing is
sometimes the most interesting thing was
just not the most recent thing. Recency
is an important input into relevance,
but it's not the only one. My sister got
engaged last night and you know she's in
Germany.
>> No, she didn't. If she did, she's
married.
>> She got married last year. That's why it
was top of mind.
>> All right.
>> But if she got engaged, you know, and I
missed it because she lives in Europe
and you know, we're different time
differences. Like, do I really want to
see a picture of like my brother's pobo
sandwich, you know, poboy sandwich, or
do I want to like see my sister's things
first? So, I I It's tough. It's tough.
I'd love to figure out a way to find the
right balance. I want to give people
agency over the experience, but I think
it needs to be in a way that creates a
system that makes sense, not just for us
as a business, which matters. I'm not
pretending that's not an issue, but also
for the overall community because we've
done chronological by default and where
you can make it default and you see not
only does usage go down, overall
sentiment goes down. the individual who
made that choice might be happy at the
moment, but when you just get pummeled
with stuff you're less interested in
over the course of months, we ask, we
run surveys at massive scales, we just
see people start to become less and less
satisfied with Instagram.
>> Kind of along these lines, uh, everybody
asks you about this these days, uh, AI
and content and how that all impacts
everything that's going on. I want to
ask you something I haven't seen someone
ask you. Is the rise of AI content uh a
headwind or a tailwind for Instagram
versus other platforms? Do you think
this helps or hurts you guys?
>> I think it's going to be a tailwind, but
I think it's going to be a challenge.
It's And not just because it's more
content. Obviously, we're an attention
business driven business. We're an
advertising business. More content means
potentially more attention. It that's
not for free, though. Like, I don't
think we're very good at ranking AI
content yet. There's great AI content.
There's crap AI content. you should just
see the stuff you're interested in and
not any of the stuff you're not
interested in. But I do think that in a
world where or for years now and I've
said this many times, power shifting
from institutions to individuals across
industries, the easiest example is
sports where players are more relevant
than teams now. And that was not the
case when I was a kid.
In that world, you're gonna I think it
behooves us to invest in individuals and
to invest in specifically for Instagram
and creators. And I mean creators
broadly. I don't just mean influencers
who are promoting branded content and
making, you know, native only videos. I
mean anybody who's using platforms like
Instagram to help do what they do,
right? It could be you could be a
journalist, you could be an artist, you
could be selling scarves you sew, but
like you're out there as yourself. for
creating and sharing content that helps
you achieve whatever it is you're trying
to do. So, we've been leaning in that
direction for many years now. That's
been our, you know, one of our two or
three most important audiences for as
long as I've been on Instagram. In a
world where there's an abundance of
synthetic content, I actually think
people are going to seek out creativity
and authenticity and people [snorts]
more, not less. And I think that that
will help us. That doesn't mean that we
won't have AI content on our platform.
There's going to be bad and good AI
content and we're going to try and
handle that, you know, the way we
normally handle content. So unsafe goes
away. Interesting versus not interesting
is based on ranking and personalization.
Um, but I think people are going to
really seek out other points of view
because Instagram was never just about
the content. It was always about to a
certain degree the person behind the
content, the point of view, the reason
they're sharing it, their perspective.
And I think that's going to become more
important, not less. And I think given
that we are not the best at a lot of
things, but we are the largest uh
creator platform, you know, you know, if
you look at how we define creators and
how many creators use us versus other
platforms, I think it'll be a tailwind
for us because I think people are going
to seek out people.
>> And this connects to your earlier point
that uh companies uh like say New York
Times can pump out a bunch of AI content
versus a creator. And so you're saying
you kind of want to protect against
that, too. Allow individuals to continue
to perform well in spite of just all
this AI content.
>> If you just love AI content, great.
Like, you should be able to have a feed
that's just like AI town. And if you
don't, then you shouldn't have it in
your feed. Like, you know, to me, it's
like I don't think we should I mean, I
understand why people are, right?
There's a I'm not oblivious to the
overall paradigm shift and sort of
revolution that we're sitting in. But I
don't think we should judge content
based on the tool that made it. Um I
think we should judge it based on the
content, the point of view, the person
behind the content. Like I don't I don't
think we should filter out AI content. I
think we should let you know if content
is AI content or not. I think we should
let you know more about the person who
posted anything so that you can make
informed decisions about whether or not
to believe or trust them based on, you
know, knowing who they are or where they
are or how many times they've changed
their profile or, you know, you know, if
their profile is three days old or three
years old. Um, but I don't think we
should be making value judgments based
on what tool you used.
>> Is there an AI uh content creator you
love that you're just like, "This is so
good. I love watching these AI videos."
Yeah. What is she called? Plastic
plastic dream sequence. Is that what it
is?
>> Um I think I'll check the name. Yeah.
Plastic dream. Uh
>> um plastic dream sequence. I have it on
my phone. I'll double check. Um it's
these like uh like sort of dolls,
Barbies, but they're like singing songs
and these little tiny little silhouettes
and snippets. And it's just it's just
amazing. It's like a little weird, but
like also kind of amazing. And it's it's
very clearly AI. It's not pretending not
to be, but it's has a very clear
creative and aesthetic point of view.
And every time I come by one, I'm like,
"Yep, we're doing this now. I'm going to
watch this for 30 seconds."
>> I have it pulled up here. And I don't I
want to watch it, but I'm not going to.
[laughter]
>> That's awesome.
>> If Only AI, that's another one. He's out
of He's in France. I think he's in
Paris. He uses multiple different tools
and models, but he kind of tries to
create these dreamscapes and animate
them. So he create uses one model to
create the image, another one to create
the video, music, etc. Uh he's like very
clearly got his own aesthetic. Um u and
he's just like you could you could think
of him as a painter, but like this is
his tool.
>> Is there kind of a vision of AI versus
human in the feed? Do you think it'll
like you said you maybe want to market
like how do you think about people? Are
they going to be like AI count, not AI
count? How do you think about or is that
still kind of a work in progress?
>> Maybe we'll end up in the same place,
but there's a difference between marking
content and marking accounts and they're
both useful and interesting. So, if
content was created with AI, I think you
should be able to know that. That's hard
by the way because we can detect that
right now, but as these models get
better, we might lose the ability to
detect that. So, we should also be very
careful to be honest with you about how
confident we are in our own sort of
assessment. Um, but I think you should
be able to just ask be like, "Hey, is
this AI?" And we should be able to tell
you. We think it probably is or we're
not sure or it's definitely not or it
definitely is. I actually think we might
be might be more practical to to label
camera captured content like basically
non-AI content as opposed to labeling AI
content long term for a couple of
reasons.
>> But then at the account level, I think
it also matters. There is definitely an
a new spam vector which is these fake
accounts which by the way an AI creator
that's fine there's nothing wrong with
that necessarily but there is there are
these spam vectors which are trying to
abuse that and you know they're selling
like you know bogus supplements and it's
like an AI monk and it doesn't present
it's not obvious that it's an AI and
it's just trying to like take advantage
of you know a certain aesthetic or a
certain sort of stereotype like we need
to figure out how to crack down on that
And so I do think I do think we should
be making sure that you know basically
you just need to know and then you can
make your own informed decision. Is the
account a real person or not? Is the
content a real piece of content or not?
>> When you think about other platforms uh
in the space social you know content
platforms are there any um features or
just or like ways of of of approaching
stuff that they do well that you're kind
of jealous of or really impressed by?
>> Yeah, there's a bunch. everybody. So
many people do so much because I mean
for me like one of the things that we
are finally catching up with but I've
been always very impressed with is Tik
Tok and their recommenders ability to
break small talent. Um, in the world of
ranking and recommenders and rank, um,
you can talk about exploitationbased
ranking. That sounds terrible, but it
just means like using the data you have.
And then you can talk about exploration
based ranking, going and trying to
figure out, you know, what someone might
be interested in that they might even
not know they're interested in yet. And
it is much easier to move engagement by
showing people stuff that, you know,
they'll probably like because lots of
people like it. it's much harder to go
and figure out how to
essentially test content so that we can
see like hey maybe you sure you like
Bieber but you might also like Afrounk
and so we're just going to like show you
some Afrounk and see what happens. If
you do the latter, this exploration
based ranking, you can I think it's
really good for niche creators and small
creators because you give them a chance
to find an audience that either wasn't
going to see them before or didn't even
know that they were interested before.
So, we've invested a lot over the last
couple years in ranking, not just
increasing engagement, but increasing
originality, increasing the number of uh
pieces of content that break out, uh
increasing recency to stay culturally
relevant. And so a lot of that has been
inspired by by Tik Tok and bite dance. I
think we're catching up. Um there's
actually a couple of those areas where
we I think by best we can tell we're
ahead of them. There's a couple where
we're still behind, but for we have line
of sight to I think being the best in
class at recommendations for the first
time um during my tenure. Uh so that's I
think and they get a lot of credit for
inspiring a lot of their work.
>> Nice job.
>> Well, we'll see. We're not there yet.
[laughter]
They call me disappointed dad. My team
is always like, "Can you ease up on the
disappointed dad vibe?" So, I'm I'm
trying to trying to be a little bit more
um generous about giving people their
flowers.
>> Like you say that, but that's an
interesting common thread across really
successful leaders is just never being
satisfied.
>> Yeah.
>> Always feeling a blessing and a curse.
>> Here's all the problem. It is. Yeah.
on this creator piece. I think that's
also, you know, people uh complain about
this global algorithm not showing them
all their friends, but I feel like this
is a benefit of what happens when you do
this now that you can break new creators
into wide audience if you have this kind
of global algorithmic feed, which is
really great for a lot of people.
>> I mean, I'm out there talking about a
lot of these contentious issues and I
get beat [clears throat] up a lot in the
comments, which is fine. My main thing
here is just to try to communicate that
there's almost always trade-offs, right?
There's that, you know, you can't just
have all of the things, unfortunately.
You know, you want to have um you you
want to never see something you're not
interested in, then you're also just
going to see like the most basic general
lowest common denominator stuff all the
time. You know, you want to discover new
and interesting things. you're
occasionally going to see stuff that was
just a miss, you know. You know, but
this isn't just true about ranking.
These all all these major debates have
trade-offs, right? You know, uh privacy
and safety, those two things are
intention. You know, do you do you want
a company scanning your messages or not?
There's some really significant
trade-offs on both sides of that debate.
Um and so generally speaking, when I
argue and engage in debate with people
who feel really strongly about things,
I'm not usually trying to convince them.
They usually their mind is usually made
up. I'm just trying to enumerate all of
the different puts and takes for the
rest of the people watching the
conversation.
>> Speaking of getting torn apart in the
comments, like you're so in the middle
and thick of all of these really hairy
situations, changing the feed, you're
like in the Cambridge Analytica lawsuit,
all this just like you're in the center
of so much controversy and is that some
>> Yep. [laughter]
Oh man. Is that just like you I will
lean into this. This is the thing I need
to do. Or was it like Zuck being like
Adam you got to be the front face of all
the stuff and get in there? Like where
does that come from?
>> It started on newsfeed. So I used to run
newsfeed at Facebook and I my take was
that the debate was going to happen with
or without us. So we might as well
participate. And so I started being
really active on Twitter specifically
because that's where journalists really
lived at the time. And I thought it
would be show some humility to show up
on their turf, so to speak. My Twitter
ended up being like the most the darkest
place in my life because I just followed
all of our biggest critics. That's not a
dig on Twitter. That was just what I
did.
>> Um, and that's where it started and it
kind of slowly built from there. For
better, for worse, we've become
a really important part of daily life
for a lot of people. We touch a lot of
people. We have a lot of responsibility
and
there's a lot of change and there's with
change means there's going to be anxiety
and stress and scrutiny. We've made
great decisions. We've made mistakes. Um
we've been criticized for things that I
think um we've been criticized unfairly.
We've been criticized fairly. And so we
just need to accept that this debate is
gonna happen broadly. So I just think
it's better for us to talk about it um
and just be clear about what we're
doing, why we're doing it, what the
trade-offs are. If people disagree,
that's okay. We're not necessarily, you
know, winning over friends when we talk
about what we do. But I think over the
long run, people are fundamentally more
afraid of things that they don't
understand um and about things where
people are more secretive and less
accessible. And so I've been tried I've
tried to show up in an accessible and
authentic way. Um and I've made mistakes
and I [snorts] have enjoyed it at times
and hated it at other times. Um but
that's kind of how it started. There was
also kind of a fun debate in Mark's sort
of senior leadership team a long time
ago where we were just talking about how
we're a social media company where we
had like a very sort of conventional
approach to communication and like press
releases and why don't we just use our
platform. So, um, I was not in that
debate, but I stuck myself into that
debate, trying to mediate it. And I
think, um, but that was also a reason
why I ended up getting sucked in,
because Mark was like, "All right, well,
let's see. Like, why don't you try and
see how it goes?"
>> What's something that helps you deal
with the the hate that flows at you
every time you say something that people
disagree with,
>> you try to put it in perspective, right?
You know, like, so it started with I did
the redesign of Newsfeed in 2009. We
launched it, March of 2009
for Facebook. I was a designer. I was a
front like an IC designer, front, you
know, entry- level designer. And the
first comment that came in was something
pretty derogatory. I think it was like
it was like homophobic and anti-semitic,
you know, it was just like literally
we're all sitting there. We launched
this thing and we're just looking at the
stream of comments and it's like the
first one and it was specifically about
they don't know me but it was like what
exploive expletive um sensor sensor uh
designed this [__] [laughter] and I was
like oh it was me. Um
and I was like devastated. I was like
25-year-old kid and I don't know I
thought about it and
I came I came to this idea that if you
spent 30 40 50 minutes a day at a at
your desk and you organized your photos
there and you wrote letters to your
friends there and you read there and
then I just came and I rearranged your
desk and I didn't tell you I didn't warn
you. I didn't even explain why. Like you
would be pissed and that would be
reasonable. Um, and that was what was
happening just, you know, with millions
of people. Um, so I try to put things in
perspective. Um, and then I try to step
away from it. Um, get time with my kids,
get time outside. Uh, there there are
months where it's really not hard at all
and there are months where it's really
really grinds on me.
>> Along those lines, there's a famous kind
of reversal when you redesign the feed
into this kind of video scrolly
experience. There's this whole
>> protest. the world protested.
>> Yeah, that was pretty rough.
>> Uh, what was kind of like, okay, wow,
we're actually not right and we should
go back. What was kind of what helped
you decide, okay, let's change course.
>> So, actually that one got that one three
or four things got conflated. We had a
redesign of feed that went to the video
viewer that was a test to 4% of users on
iOS. It was a not it was not going to
roll out. It was just like an early test
to get some sense and feedback on the
idea. We were also leaning into reels a
lot. We were also leaning into
recommendations, so posts from accounts
you don't follow a lot. And there were
also creators who were upset about the
fact that their reach was going down and
they were blaming ranking changes on
that. Those four things got all
conflated. We had some pretty bigname
creators publicly like
slap us. Then the press covered that
creator sort of backlash which then got
more creators doing it. So we ended up
with this little bit of like a
multiplier effect or echo between the
creator community and the press back and
forth, but we were never going to launch
that. That was an early test. We were we
knew it was needed work. Um we actually
have continued to grow video and invest
in creative tools and invest in ranking
and invest in recommendations and that's
driven in most of our growth in the
years since. um
>> I think we were pushed well I don't know
doesn't feel like but like it I think we
were I think my real takeaway wasn't
that we should have not tested that
design necessarily I think we could have
been we could have done a bunch of
things better to explain and maybe move
a little fast move a little slower I
think we were just pushing things a
little bit too fast and when you are
responsible for a platform like
Instagram you need to be reasonable and
realistic about how much you can evolve
it Now, I would much rather have
backlashes like that every couple years
or continue to evolve and continue to
stay relevant than the alternative,
which would have been like we didn't
have video, we didn't have DMs, we
didn't have stories, we didn't have
ranking, and we wouldn't be on having
this podcast right now. Um
um but the cost of leaning in is that
you're going to occasionally like make a
mistake and you're going to definitely
um pay for it. It's interesting how
running experiments now is like very
risky for companies at your scale. One
person spots it and they're like, "Oh
shit."
>> You kind of need to have a press.
You don't need to be proactive about
communicating it, but you need to have a
calm strategy. Like we can't for any for
any design change or any test that could
be controversial. We we talk about it
beforehand and be like, "Okay, not if it
leaks, when it leaks, what are we
saying?" You know, are we, you know,
should we talk about proactively, should
we talk reactively? Either way, what's
the message? Because you can't you can't
you can't launch something to three
billion people and
not test it first, but you can't test
something at our scale and not expect
people to cover it and not and be so you
have to be ready to talk about it before
you even know you want to launch it. Um
so it's um it makes the development
cycle more complicated than it used to
be.
>> Yeah. the uh head of growth at Enthropic
launched an experiment with pricing and
it just went crazy on Twitter. He's like
hold that 1% of people were just trend
stuff like noic
>> pricing particularly that one is a real
you got to be real careful with that
one. I've I've learned we've all learned
these lessons. We should all share notes
more. That's what I think.
>> Here's one not to how to avoid the
internet hating you for the day.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I'm happy to talk to that
more than
[laughter]
>> I think he's all right. He's all right.
Okay. Okay, I'm going to take us to two
recurring corners on the podcast. Fail
corner and hot seat corner. Fail corner.
What's uh what's something that you
worked on that was just a huge failure
that helped you become better?
>> Oh, a bunch. Um
>> so any
>> So I'll give you two maybe. So before
Instagram, my first project as a PM was
on a project called Facebook Home, which
was a sort of
>> fork of Android um at the operating
system level and and a piece of hardware
with HTC. It was a spectacular failure.
I learned way more in that year, year
and a half, and I did it any year. I
think probably in my career because I
was just a design manager before that. I
declared myself a PM because the PM on
the project quit and I just threw myself
head first in understanding carriers and
OEMs and uh certification as well as
Android and operating systems and just
lend a ton. Um so and I'm happy I
brought that project to an end because
it had been going on for a long time and
sometimes you the best thing you can do
is execute an idea that doesn't have
market fit well just to decide whether
or not the idea was a good idea in the
first place.
Another big mistake I made um during my
Instagram tenure was the first version
of reels was built on top of stories.
Stories had a ton of momentum. This was
I think 2019
and we were trying to build reels into
stories because we were trying to build
in the thing that was growing the
fastest. But it was not a strong
foundation. Most, you know, the
readthrough rate on stories is
relatively low. There's way more stories
than most people have time to consume.
So most of the reels were never seen and
then they disappeared. Um, and if we had
the version of reels that we launched in
like mid maybe I think it's like the
summer of 2020 in the summer of 2019.
I think I don't think Tik Tok isn't I
think Tik Tok is still big and
important, but I don't think it's as big
as it is now because when they really
took off was when the pandemic hit and a
bunch of people had a lot of time at
home and were looking for a little bit
of joy and were totally fine with their
phone having sound on. And so if you
look at the numbers, the 2020 is when
they exploded and we were out of
position. And um on one hand, you know,
I'm a designer. I'm trying to not add
new things to the product. I'm trying to
extend existing primitives and that was
the idea. On the other hand, I was wrong
and and it's a pretty big fork in the
road if you just look at the overall
business over the last eight years.
>> We created a lot of economic opportunity
in the world allowing Tik Tok to to
grow.
>> That's good. I'm I'm glad they exist.
>> Okay, final question. Um I'm curious
just about your screen time policy with
your kids. I know you have three kids.
Uh there's a lot of concern these days
about Instagram not being great for
people, not for kids. A lot of tech
executives don't let their kids use
devices while they're building the
product. As head of Instagram, how do
you think about screen time with your
kids?
>> The key thing for me is boundaries. Um
it's also about education and being and
having conversations with them. But my
kids are too young to use social media.
They're 10, eight, and six. Um but they
each have an iPad. they
get um they have to earn their time. Um
so they have different ways they earn
that time. It's usually about like
sitting down to do your homework three
times for half an hour each gets you a
total of 90 minutes on the weekend and
then they can use that time on the
weekend. Um but you kind of have to set
that boundary where it's like you can't
just like you know it can't just be they
ask for it and you give it to them. I
think that matters a lot and then I'm
pretty opinionated about what they do on
it. Like I approve what apps that they
have. I think parents should be
approving what apps kids specifically
are um downloading onto their devices.
We've been advocating for this at a
policy level for a long time at Meta. I
think those things help a lot. Um there
are some exceptions. Um
one is planes. It's just like about
surviving. I don't know if you've ever
for those of you are parents.
>> I'm going to be Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's like you just like that's
just like all right you know we're fly
you know it's a 10-hour flight or eight
hour flight. It's like, yeah, just just
you just need to get through it. Um, the
other one that I'm starting to
experiment with my 10-year-old with is
so schools are interesting because I
think I'm pretty supportive of a no
phone in classrooms. Um, that's
happening more and more. I think that's
is probably good for education. And I do
also know in the world of AI that
there's concern about kids using AI and
not learning critical thinking skills.
And I think that's a valid concern. But
I also am worried about kids not
learning how to leverage AI and then
being sort of at a disadvantage. So
that's a balance. So I think you need
both. So with with my eldest, we started
um vibe coding recently together. Um
he's just loves video games. So I was
like, "All right, let's make a video
game." And so he's made this 19 level
platformer game that kind of looks like
an eight-bit version of Super Mario from
when I was a kid. But like each level
has its own theme, its own types of
monsters. There's a store where you can
buy different skins or weapons, and
there's like uh like all it's
unbelievable what a 10-year-old who
still types with three fingers can do um
with just, you know, a couple hours of
sitting together. But that is more of
like a I want you to learn how to
um make things. I I want you to be
thinking, not just playing games and I'm
gonna sit with you and do we're going to
do this together. Um so to me, these are
the things that matter. Boundaries um
scoping it down to the activities you
think are healthy for your kid. Every
kid is different. U but I do think you
want your kids to be digitally literate,
um AI literate, because I think if
they're not, they're going to be at a
disadvantage. But it's you also don't
want it to be a free-for-all.
>> This is selfishly useful for me as a as
a I have a three-year-old and I'm trying
to figure all this stuff out. So, this
is useful.
>> Oh, yeah. No,
>> we need to figure out a strategy.
>> It's amaz It's a thing. And you're
you're you're not that far off. You're
really just not that far off. It's going
to happen in a couple years.
>> Five coding next year. Let's do it.
>> I couldn't believe I tried to do it six
months ago and it just totally didn't
work. And then
>> now with newer models, it's been
amazing.
>> What's their platform of choice? Are
they a clock coding team? uh person.
>> Yeah, my 10-year-old is using is using
cloud code right now. Um
>> um but um we will see. We'll see how
that goes.
>> Adam, uh I'm going to let you go. Thank
you so much for being here. This you're
just like such a gem of a person. It's
just so obvious how clear like how
authentic you are and just like how
deeply you think about everything. Uh so
I really appreciate you being here.
>> I appreciate you bringing me on. Um been
a fan for a long time. It's nice to
finally get to have a conversation.
>> I appreciate that. I really appreciate
that. Uh let me just ask you this final
question to ask everyone. What's a way
that listeners can be useful to you?
>> I just think you don't even have to tell
this to other people, but just remember
that
this world and technology is complicated
and there are almost always tradeoffs.
Um and you can totally disagree with the
decisions I or we make. Um, but just
remember that we are people here trying
to make these decisions, trying to do
the best we can. And I I actually do
invite the criticism and the critique
and the feedback, but um, but know that
none of these contentious debates are
nearly as simple as most people pretend
to make them out to be.
>> Wise words, Adam, thank you so much for
being here.
>> Pleasure. Thank you, Lenny.
>> Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for
listening. If you found this valuable,
you can subscribe to the show on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider
giving us a rating or leaving a review
as that really helps other listeners
find the podcast. You can find all past
episodes or learn more about the show at
lennispodcast.com.
See you in the next episode.